Gabriel Cisneros

(562) 991-2474 | GabrielCee81@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabe-cisneros

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience with an emphasis in React. I am currently the team lead of Seller Retention at The RealReal which involves working in a fast-pace agile environment and ensuring seller facing features are delivered on time. Having a preference for frontend, I am excited about any opportunity involving customer facing React applications.

EXPERIENCE

The RealReal Remote

Senior Full Stack Engineer

Dec 2021 - Current

Full Stack Engineer

Nov 2020 - Dec 2021

- Lead the migration of our seller dashboard, My Sales, to a Next.js app using Typescript and Apollo Client.
- Create backend solutions for Rails and Phoenix applications which include maintaining Stripe webhooks, REST endpoints for consignment information, and creating Plaid Link GraphQL mutations.
- Lead the adoption of Next's Incremental Static Regeneration functionality for Prismic (CMS) pages which improved Lighthouse Performance scores by 7 points on average.
- Help team growth by conducting interviews, mentoring an intern, and being active in our JAMstack Guild.

H.O.M.E. Remote

Freelance Full Stack Developer

April 2020 - Nov 2020

- Designed and developed a video course web application with Diango, React, PostgreSQL, and AWS S3.
- Communicated with client on a weekly basis to review progress and create achievable deliverables.
- Implemented Redux-like state with React's Context and Reducer hooks to keep video angles in sync.

Conventus San Francisco, CA

Full Stack Developer

May 2019 - June 2020

- Part of a team which developed an internal loan management application with Django and React.
- Created a socket.io, Node micro-service to enable real-time loan editing which helped avoid hours of work being lost due to employees overwriting each others changes.
- Implemented a price forecast chart powered by HouseCanary and Zillow APIs.

JAKKS Pacific Santa Monica, CA

Full Stack Developer Intern

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Participated in improving the company's intranet php website used by over 700 employees by being engaged in scrum meetings, creating solutions upon ticket submission, and executing automated Selenium frontend tests.

PROJECTS

EEG Processing Flask App (Capstone Project)

Jan 2019 - May 2019

- Built a Flask web application for researchers to upload EEG files (scans of electrical activity in the brain) and download the processed results.
- Created a backend for file pre-processing, optimized the existing Python processing script, and utilized AWS S3 Bucket for cloud storage.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programing Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Elixir, Ruby, C, C++

Frameworks: Next.js, Django, Flask, Express, Phoenix, Rails

Web Technologies: React, HTML/CSS, GraphQL, Apollo Client, Node, Chakra UI, Sass, JWT, Bootstrap

Database Systems: PostgreSQL, AWS S3, AWS DynamoDB (noSQL)

EDUCATION

University of San Francisco

San Francisco, CA

Aug 2015 - May 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

• Cumulative GPA: 3.64; **Major GPA: 3.77 / 4.0**

• Relevant Courses: Data Structures & Algorithms, Software Development, Database Systems, Web Development, Parallel Programming, Computer Architecture, Operating Systems and Language Paradigms